Hey everyone, thanks for listening to
the Grow Your Life podcast. My name is
Jeremiah Kowski and on this podcast I
help coaches, mentors, and trainers
scale their businesses to make more
money and reach the life they've always
wanted. Now, I want to talk today about
credit. I've not talked about credit
before on this podcast or on this
channel. This is not a credit repair
channel. This is not a channel about um
getting credit or funding as far as that
goes. But I want to talk about why it's
important to get your credit game in
order as a business owner. One of the
problems that I noticed and I meet a lot
of people is that they say, "I don't
have money. I don't have funds. I don't
have access to resources, credit to be
able to build my business." And this is
a problem because if you want to be
successful as a coach or a mentor, you
need to have access to capital. You need
to be able to pay for different
software, marketing, advertising, be
able to outsource and hire teams and be
able to do stuff like that. And
oftentimes you might need to float it a
couple of months until the revenue
starts to come in. If you follow my
channel, I talk about strategies and
ways that you can use evergreen offers
to be able to create the kind of income
that you want to create for yourself
that's going to make you six and seven
figures online. And how we've been able
to do that in our businesses over the
years. I've been in this industry for
the last oh gosh 22 years. 20 I I say
it's 22 or 23. 22 years. 2003 is when I
got into this industry
and I've learned everything there there
is to know about it. I built multiple
coaching businesses over the 8 figure a
year mark. That's over $10 million a
year.
And it I can tell you unequivocally that
if you want to be able to make the kind
of money that's possible for you or you
just want to make six figures that you
got to have access to capital, you can
hire a coach. You can hire a mentor like
me. I can become a mentor to you to show
you how to be able to get those clients.
How to be able to get your offers out
there to get more people buying from you
and purchasing from you. And so then
that's what I love to do with people is
show them exactly what it takes, exactly
what to do to be able to get people to
become their clients in this
marketplace, in this industry. So having
access to credit helps with that. We all
know what it's like to not have access
to capital and credit. So I'm not going
to talk about that, okay? But I want to
just paint a scenario for you of what it
looks like if you can start to repair
that. If you could start to pay off your
credit card debt, that's one of the
first things that you that you want to
do. you want to be able to cut back on
your expenses. You you're going to need
to tighten up the belt quite a bit on
those things and then find ways to
increase your income to be able to do
that. Now, one of the ways that can
actually repair your credit and there's
a couple of things that you can do. I
actually did this a little bit myself is
you can borrow money. Listen, hear me
out. You can borrow money with a
different debt instrument. whether it be
a business loan. I was able to get this
off of the revenue that I had in my
business. So then it didn't go on my
personal credit to pay off my personal
credit. That boosted my personal credit
scores. I kept everything tight until
both were paid off and then boom, I shot
way up in my to to an 800 credit score.
And so because of this, what I was able
to do is I was able to borrow over here
to pay off over here. And within less
than 6 months, it completely changed my
financial tra trajectory. It allowed me
to have multiple six figures in the
bank. It allowed me to be able to invest
as much as I want to in my business. It
allowed me to have access to hundreds of
thousands of dollars in capital that I
can be able to to build everything with.
And to now we're starting to deploy
that. We're starting to see the results
of that. We're starting to see that
immediately now we've been able to bring
in multiple extra six figures that is
coming in because of being able to do
this and I've taken a slow and steady
approach to it. What I did is I repaired
my credit and I didn't go straight out
there to try to spend the money or
invest it or things like that. I just
had it as a war chest, an arsenal that I
could deploy when the good ideas start
to come up when I start to have clarity
on what to do and my offers and things
like that. And it's taken me about 9
months to be able to figure exactly what
that is out and and immediately I go
boom, let's do this. Let's take action
on this because I have the capital,
because I have I have access to the
resources, because I have access to be
able to do that. And then here's the
great part about having access to credit
that you can do is you can then roll
this into other passive investments. And
what this allows you to do is that you
can actually cash flow your business
from other cash flowing assets such as
stocks, um, bonds, real estate, things
like that, depending on what market that
you're in. And then you can use those to
cash flow what you're doing in your
business. So you have other streams of
income that are coming in that are
funded by your access to credit. Now you
got to be careful with this because you
can get overleveraged and if you're
spending the money and you're not
keeping really good track of what's
happening and the amount of profit
that's coming in, you can lose your
shorts. So be very careful with this.
But having access to capital opens up so
much opportunity for you that you don't
have because you can outsource when you
need to. You can run an ad campaign and
and whether it makes money or doesn't it
be it's not a stretch for you. You can
pay for your softwares. You can pay for
all these different types of things by
being able to do this. And this is what
the wealthy know how to do. The
wealthiest people in America,
in the world, use credit
not to buy things,
but to take,
say, you borrow $50,000. You take that
borrowed $50,000 and you turn it into
$150,000.
And now you have $100,000 more from
money that wasn't even your own money by
simply getting your credit in alignment.
Now, how do you build up to those levels
where you have hundreds of thousands of
dollars that you have access to? Well,
you got to show that you're responsible
with a smaller amount. Generally, as you
repair your credit, you'll only get
access to maybe a $1,000 credit card
here or a $5,000 one there. That's okay.
Here's what happens. Because a lot of
the banks make money on you, and this is
this is a real credit hack right here.
They make money on you as you spend
money. And even if you pay off it, they
make money on the amount that you're
spending. They make a percentage of that
in merchant fees.
As you spend on these cards, they will
start to increase your limits. And it is
an incredibly important thing for you to
request credit limit increases sometimes
every 30 to 60 days. Because what'll
happen is they can increase it two,
three, even four times to where you
could have a card with a $40,000 limit,
$50,000 limit. I got multiple cards like
that. And are you going to use it? No.
Now, it might make you feel
uncomfortable that you have all this
unused capital that you have access to,
but what if you needed to use it or
there was an opportunity that showed up
and you could take advantage of it at
any time that you wanted to? Now, you
got to stay responsible. You got to not
be just a spender. You got to make sure
that you're bringing in more than you're
spending.
But if you can do this and you do this
the right way,
you can create wealth for yourself.
And so
pay off your debt,
start spending, and then paying it down
within your means on those cards.
Raise your credit limits. This will then
increase your credit score even more
and then use the capital to
invest, buy ads,
create more cash flow for yourself in
your business, hire some people
to do the things that you need to do
instead of sitting around
because
you can sit around and say, "Well, I
paid off all my debt, so now I don't
have to worry about anything." I mean,
you know, everything's great now, but
here's the thing. You have the potential
to leverage that
with the knowledge that you have and the
knowledge that I provide inside of my
coaching programs
and with what I share with people when
I'm one-on-one coaching them to be able
to get better results
than you could just on your own with
just cash.
And so this is why I I encourage people
get better financial literacy habits.
Don't just buy a bunch of stuff you
don't need. My wife and I, we have
access to this capital and we do not
spend more than our means.
Now, as our income goes up, we start to
enjoy certain things. We bought a second
car. I bought a Tesla Model 3 because
it's only 300 bucks a month.
cheap. Uh, you know, we're going to go
on a vacation. First time we went on a
vacation on our own in years with the
family
as this money starts to come in.
And okay, if things tighten back up, we
know how to do that. We know how to
adjust. We know how to eb and flow. We
know how to live below our means and
then utilize the access to capital to
increase our means overall. And this is
where that responsibility comes from.
It's not the Dave Ramsey approach. It's
not the like while he's awesome, the
Dave Ramsey approach really keeps you
kind of
operating in a poverty mindset. And you
got to get out of that poverty mindset
and into an abundance mindset and
realize that listen, it is about your
habits. It is about making sure that you
have good money habits or you can get
into a bankruptcy hole that you do not
want to get into. But if you can have
and develop good habits, you can
leverage
your income and your credit to make far
more money than you ever thought
possible. All right, listen. And I'd
love to mentor you on what to do, what
actions to take, how to get more
clients, what to build, how to create
the kind of offers that generate sales
in your business. That's what I' that's
what I help people with every single
week inside of my Wealthy Coach Academy
program, inside my VIP 101 experience.
We'll talk soon. Have a good one.
[Applause]
[Music]